Fundamental factors can also be used in the cross-sectional risk factor model.
基本面因子还可以用于横截面风险因子模型
In fact we'll discuss two that we saw in the Fama-French time series model,
我们将讨论在 Fama-French 时间序列模型中见过的两个因子
the book to market value and market cap.
即账面市值比和市值
This is an interesting example because we can see that
这个示例比较有趣 因为我们发现
there are two approaches to working with the same factor.
同一因子可以有两种处理方法
There's the method we saw using a time series risk factor model,
我们之前见过使用时间序列风险因子模型的方法
and now we'll see how to do this with the cross-sectional risk factor model.
现在我们将学习如何在横截面风险因子模型中使用它们
Just to revisit our goal,
回顾下我们的目标
we're going to fill in the values to calculate the portfolio variance.
我们将填充这些值 来计算投资组合方差
For starters, let's see what data we already have to work with.
首先我们看看已经有哪些数据
For each stock, we have a book to market value,
对于每支股票 我们知道账面市值比
which may be updated once every three months if the company is based in the US.
美国公司每隔三个月更新一次账面市值比
We also have a market cap,
还知道市值
which may be updated daily.
可能会每天更新
These values can be set as the factor exposures.
这些值可以设为因子暴露度
Notice that in the Fama-French time series model,
注意 在 Fama-French 时间序列模型中
the book to market and market cap,
账面市值比和市值
were used in theoretical long-short portfolios to set the factor returns.
在理论做多-做空投资组合中用于设置因子收益率
However, for the cross-sectional model,
但是 对于横截面模型
these values are used directly as the factor exposures instead.
这些值直接用作因子暴露度
We can also obtain the stock returns,
我们还可以获取股票收益率
and we want to estimate the factor returns using regression.
我们希望通过回归估算因子收益率
So, we'll take the following steps.
我们将采取以下步骤
For all the stocks in the selected stock universe,
第一步 对于所选股票池中的所有股票
obtain each stock's factor exposures,
获取每支股票的因子暴露度
which are the book to market value and market cap.
即账面市值比和市值
Also get each stock's return for one time period.
第二步 获得每支股票在每个时段的收益率
Next, request the stock return against the factor exposures.
第三步 根据因子暴露度回归地得出股票收益率
The regression estimates the factor return for each of the two factors.
回归过程会估算两个因子中的每个因子的收益率
Since this factor return is estimated based on all the stocks in the stock universe,
因为这个因子收益率是根据股票池中所有股票估算出来的
it is general enough to apply to all those stocks.
所以它适用于所有这些股票
Notice that in practice,
注意 在实践中
even if the stock universe is 9,000 stocks,
即使股票池有 9,000 支股票
we may use a subset of those stocks to perform the regression.
我们可能只使用股票子集进行回归运算
This subset is called the estimation universe
这个子集称为估算股票池
because it's the stock universe that is used for estimating these model parameters.
因为它是用来估算这些模型参数的股票池
To get a time series of factor returns,
为了获得因子收益率时间序列
repeat this process of performing a multiple regression for each day.
我们针对每一天重复回归
Once we obtain a time series of factor returns,
获得因子收益率时间序列后
we can calculate factor variances and
我们计算因子方差和协方差
covariances to fill in the covariance matrix of factors.
并填充到因子协方差矩阵中
To fill in the matrix of specific variances,
为了填充特有方差矩阵
we can calculate the specific return from the stock return
我们可以用股票收益率减去根据所选因子
minus the estimated stock return using the chosen factors.
得出的估算股票收益率 算出特有收益率
The variance of the specific return time series for each stock
我们将每支股票的特有收益率方差时间序列
is what we'll use to fill in the matrix of specific variances.
填充到特有方差矩阵中